Cory Marshman

Charlotte, NC 28204 | Phone: 980-228-8926 | Email: marshman.cory@gmail.com LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/cory-marshman-6aba24152/ | GitHub: www.github.com/cmarshman | Portfolio: https://cmarshman.github.io/myportfolio/index.html

SUMMARY

I am a seasoned operations and project manager with 10+ years of management and business development experience. I have a verifiable history of contributing directly to company growth and expansion. My professional growth is focused on Full Stack Web Development, multi-million dollar project management, budget forecasting, fundraising, program development, team leadership and training, technology solutions, and operations and project management.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- HTML5
- CSS3 / Bootstrap
- JavaScript / jQuery
- REST APIs and Ajax
- NodeJS and Express JS
- MySQL / Sequelize ORM
- Socket IO

- MongoDB
- ReactJS and React Hooks
- GitHub and Heroku
- Blockchain
- AWS Amazon Managed Blockchain
- Mac/Windows OS

- Firebase
- Auth0, Bcrypt, and JWT
- MVC file structure
- Command Line Interface
- Foundation, Bulma and Materialize
- QuickBooks

WORK EXPERIENCE

SENIOR OPERATIONS MANAGER

SKIPPER. INC.

Oct 2019 - Present

CHARLOTTE, NC

Oversee all product lines. Set strategy for all product lines, analyze ROI, create more efficient operations and update procedures to reflect industry best practices. Analyze supply and demand trends to ensure needs are met. Advise on resolutions of high-level clients.

- Technologies: React.is, React Native, JavaScript, Node.is, Tableau, Figma and MapAnything API
- Increased overall efficiency by 45%, by developing and implementing a retraining program for staff.
- Increased overall margins by 10%, through data based modeling and increasing pricing.
- Manage over 70 staff members across multiple product lines and locations, while using g a proprietary tech-enabled platform to track over 70 staff members, across multiple service lines/

DIRECTOR OF OPERATIONS

FEB 2018 – OCT 2019

INNER PEAKS

CHARLOTTE. NC

Head 3 facilities totaling over 65,000 sqft. which serviced 1800+ monthly members and 20000+ monthly day pass users. Directed operations and logistics of 25+ local and regional programs and events within the last year, with 2000+ participants, negotiated vendor contracts, track individual program performance and expenses.

- Increased overall memberships by 20%, through developing a corporate membership program.
- Developed and collaborated with the ownership group on a \$4-Million 18,0000 sq. ft. new facility, with a focus on strategic business growth, risk mitigation and facility development.

PROGRAM MANAGER

Ост 2015 – Feв 2018

US National Whitewater Center

CHARLOTTE, NC

Oversaw 200+ staff members, who served up to 3500 guests across 1,300 acres and over 12 adventure activity types per day, as a part of a 5-person management team. Pioneered and operated the world's first permanent deep-water solo climbing program as well as the world's first deep water solo-climbing specific aquatics program.

 Increased overall client base by over 800 people a day, by constructing and managing a \$4 million outdoor deep-water climbing facility ESL Instructor Dec 2008 – Oct 2015

USA, SOUTH KOREA, CHINA, MYANMAR AND OMAN

Taught general, conversational and business English, locally & internationally to students. Organized and hosted English seminars and events for groups of up to 150 students. Engineered curriculum and new study material for courses directed towards students ranging from kindergarten to Professional Adults.

• Traveled to over 35 countries, across 5 continents, completed a 2800-mile unassisted cycling trip across China and a 300-mile unassisted hiking trip through the Sagarmatha region of Nepal.

PROJECTS

GIFTIFY; PROJECT LEAD - GROUP PROJECT

Gітнив: https://github.com/cmarshman/Giftify |

DEPLOYED URL: https://giftify-project2.herokuapp.com/

- A multifunctional application stores persistent user data using Sequelize DB and utilizing JawsDB to deploy to through Heroku. The user is able to login, search gift options through an Etsy API, find video descriptions of products embedded in models once selected. They are also able to search an auto populating database which allows the user to search 2019 most popular gifts and receive results instantaneously.
- Core Responsibilities: Project Lead, developed most of the front end, api and html routes, Algolia DB, Sequelize database set up and inner-join with passport authentication
- Tools / Languages Used: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Express.js, Node.js, Passport, Bcrypt Sequelize DB, MySQLWorkbench, MySQL, JawsDB, Algolia DB, Heroku, Github

REACT TASK MANAGER; SELF DEPLOYED APPLICATION

Gітнив: https://github.com/cmarshman/react_task_manager |

DEPLOYED URL: https://shielded-island-39719.herokuapp.com/

- A dynamic React application that utilizes a 3rd party API and allows users to add tasks, check them off and delete them.
- Core Responsibilities: This is a personal project coded solely by myself.
- Tools / Languages Used: HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Node.js, React.js, Axios, Typicode APIHeroku. Github

INTUITIVE BANANA; PROJECT LEAD - GROUP PROJECT

Gітнив: https://github.com/cmarshman/IntuitiveBanana

DEPLOYED URL: https://drbailey13.github.io/IntuitiveBanana/index.html

- A multifunctional music application utilizing a bulma.io framework and multiple 3rd party API's, allowing
 you to search your favorite artists, follow trending musicians, check the top 5 trending songs on
 Billboard, read up on the most recent music news, check out local concerts and follow the links to buy
 tickets
- Core Responsibilities: Project lead, developed initial front-end wire frame, Music News page and NY Times API
- Tools / Languages Used: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, NT Times API, Ticketmaster API, Audio-DB API, Github

EDUCATION

Web Development | Coding Certificate; University of North Carolina at Charlotte, Charlotte, NC | 2020 A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS

Bachelor of Arts in Anthropology: University of North Carolina at Charlotte, Charlotte, NC | 2008 Biological and Evolutionary Anthropology